《斯巴达克斯：血与沙》
《传说》
斯巴达克斯
Spartacus!
你的猛攻犹如盲人把烛
You charge without thought.
对手会利用这个弱点扭转战局
A weakness an opponent could turn to advantage.
我抓住破绽 主动出击而已
A difficult feat from his backside.
你说话也不假思索
You speak without thought as well.
这是另一个弱点
Another weakness.
色雷斯人
Thracians.
只会仰面朝天 搔首弄姿
Always on their backs with their legs spread.
跟这里格格不入
Where they belong.
进入了训练场 就得洗心革面
Forget everything you learned outside these walls.
墙外是普通人的世界
For that is the world of men.
我们不是普通人
We are more!
我们是角斗士
We are gladiators!
学习
Study.
训练
Train.
流血
Bleed.
终有一天 你会成为传奇
And one day your name will be legend
令人敬如神明 畏如雷霆
Spoken in hushed whispers of fear and awe.
就像卡普亚的冠军 克雷斯一样
As the city speaks of Crixus the champion of Capua!
他的威武并不是与生俱来
But his legend was not birthed in the arena.
而是后天铸就
It was given life here.
在这个训练场里
In this ludus.
在我的皮鞭下淬炼出来的
Under the sting of my whip!
进攻
Attack!
集合
Attend!
锻造神之节即将到来
The vulcanalia is announced!
锻造神之节
Vulcanalia?
为了纪念火神伏尔肯的节日
A festival to ward off wildfires.
在今年的锻造神之节 巴蒂塔斯主人
Dominus Batiatus has seen fit to fight twenty
决定派二十个人参加
at this year's Vulcanalia.
这是献给卡普亚人民的礼物
His gift to the people of Capua!
等级最低的竞技清晨开始
Our lowest shall fight at dawn.
之后还有八组
Eight pairs to follow.
而之后 主人会有请他的骁将
After which your master will present his primus.
最强的两人 进入竞技场决斗
Two of our finest to meet in the arena!
会有克雷斯 对吗
Crixus then?
肯定有他
Crixus certainly.
他的对手呢
And his opponent?
和卡普亚的冠军决斗必死无疑
Against the champion of Capua?
是谁又有什么关系
What would it matter?
二十个人
Twenty men
为了锻造神之节我奉献出了二十个人
I pledge twenty men to fill the ranks of the Vulcanalia
自掏腰包赚吆喝
my own coin to see each victor paid
而我又能从行政官那里得到什么好处呢
what thanks do I get from the magistrate?
他还说由于「某些急事」
He fears he will be unable to attend our reception
可能无法参加我们决赛前的欢迎晚宴
on the eve of the games due to "Pressing concerns"!
什么急事
Of what sort?
听说是他要和索罗尼斯一起进餐
I hear rumor he dines with solonius instead.
索罗尼斯
Solonius?
但是节日上他连一个人都没有派
But he offers not one man for the Vulcanalia.
而他却依旧光天化日的
Yet his tongue still manages to find his way
拍行政官的马屁
to the magistrate's asshole.
是新做的发型吗
Is that new?
为欢迎晚宴准备的
For the reception yes.
为晚宴花费越来越多 很烦恼
The rising cost of this thing raises concern.
机难轻失
It raises opportunity.
我明白
I question not its import.
不过花费太大了
I question its scale.
这场干旱让我们山穷水尽了
This drought has stretched our resources thin
现在行政官又不出席…
and now without the attendance of the magistrate…
亲爱的 小财不出大财不入
Darling you must spend coins to receive coins.
还是你教我的
My husband taught me that.
真是一个聪明人
A wise man.
你成算在心
He has his moments.
而这次也不会例外
And this will be one of them.
你会克服万难
You'll delight and astound
重振威风的
securing business for the year to come.
或许还可以诱惑葛雷博的妻子
And perhaps even tempt Glaber's wife
让她给你赞助
to take up the cause of patronage.
伊莉西娅吗
Ilithyia?
我以为她还在罗马
I thought she was still in rome
陪她那个忘恩负义的丈夫呢
with that ungrateful husband of hers.
她为了看竞技偷跑过来了
She returns absent him for the games.
她对角斗士们兴趣盎然
She's acquiring quite a taste for them.
我们可以投其所好
One which I shall nourish to advantage.
新发色很适合你
This new color suites you.
想让我把其他地方的毛发也染了吗
Oh shall I dye the rest to match?
那只鸟应该被抓来吃了
The bird would be better served in my bowl.
那它就是你最后的晚餐了
Odds the meal would be your last.
巴尔卡
Barca?
他空有其表
He stands but tall.
他满负盛名
He stands a legend.
迦太基被罗马打败后
After Carthage suffered defeat by the romans
数以百计的迦太基人
they forced hundreds of his people
在竞技场内被迫自相残杀
to fight against each other in the arena.
半天之后 只有两人幸存
Half a day passed and only two remained…
巴尔卡
Barca.
和他们的酋长
And the chief of his people
著名的玛格
The noble Mago.
玛格拥有精湛的武艺
Skill and the testament of years were his allies.
巴尔卡的优势则是年轻力胜
Strength and youth Barca's.
终于 玛格倒下了
Mago fell to his knees…
巴尔卡变成了迦太基的猛兽
And Barca became the beast of Carthage.
他只不过送一个老家伙归西了而已
He sent an old man on his way.
玛格是所向匹敌的骁勇斗士
Mago was a warrior fierce renown.
多少次血战沙场
A chief upon a throne of blood.
据说 他还是巴尔卡的父亲
He was also Barca's father as the story tells.
是事实吗
Is it true?
在角斗士的世界里
In the world of the gladiator
只有威名和荣耀才能铸就事实
A man's fame and glory constructs its own truth.
威名和荣耀
Fame and glory.
二者我都无心追觅
I seek neither.
那就是为财 像我一样
Coin then. Like me…
开门
Open the gates.
让守卫各就各位
Have the guard ready.
稍等 主人
A moment dominus.
过来说话
Ten paces.
有我妻子的消息吗
Is there any news of my wife?
她被卖给了一个叙利亚商人
She was indeed sold to a Syrian merchant.
你找到她了
You found her?
听说她现在在奥伦特河的渡船上
I have cause to believe she sails upon the Orontes.
那就是要去大马士革了
To damascus then?
或是安提俄克（古叙利亚首都）
Or perhaps Antioch?
你当我他妈的是指向标啊
Do I appear a fucking arrow my nose pointing towards
能直指你老婆那淫液肆虐的大腿
Your wife's dripping thighs!?!
别不知好歹
You press beyond position!
主人
Dominus.
你只需知道 搜寻还在继续
The search continues that's all you need to know
找到她之前 你得战斗 赢得胜利
Until then fight win.
她的自由需要你付出高昂的代价
The price of her freedom requires substantial sums on your part.
太普通了 给我看点有特色的
Too common Show me something of note.
稍等 我正好有一样
A moment. I have just the thing.
这是最好的一串
My finest piece.
是花大价钱从锡西厄的矿区
A flawless gem imported at great cost
进口来的无暇宝石
From the mines of Scythia.
开价多少 三十第纳尔
Price? Thirty denarii.
三十
Thirty?
这一串
This piece.
伊莉西娅会喜欢吗
Is it something that Ilithyia would favor?
如果要向她展示 我只会拿这串的
It's the only piece I'd show her.
她的品位非常高雅
She has very refined tastes.
二十五第纳尔
Twenty-five.
二十九第纳尔
Twenty-nine.
二十八 不同意我就把你从阳台上丢下去
Twenty-eight and I'll resist pitching you off the balcony.
那就二十八吧
Twenty-eight then.
过来
Come along then.
第二式 预备
Form two! Ready!
一
One.
第一式 预备
Form one ready!
一
One…
二
Two…
第二式
Form two.
预备
Ready!
一
One…
二
Two.
第三式
Form three!
起立
Stand.
斯巴达克斯
Spartacus!
你想被丢到矿区吗
Do you dream of the mines?
我脑子里只有浴血奋战 多科特
My focus is on blood and battle doctore.
但你的训练表现却很不及格
Yet your training proves you worthy of neither.
我是一名色雷斯人
I am a thracian.
浴血奋战是我的天性
It is in my blood.
色雷斯
Thrace.
用尿浇出来的不毛之地
A swamp of piss.
跪下
Kneel.
汝自何方来 不足为意
The lands from which you hail matters no longer.
唯吾之号令 履下之地
The only thing that does is the sound of my voice…
重若泰山
And the sand beneath your feet.
汝等必敬之如桑梓
You will learn to worship it.
继续训练
Back to training.
现在这片土地有色雷斯的味道了
The sand smells like Thrace.
也许我该拉坨屎来成全它的芳香
Perhaps I should shit to complete the aroma.
有人传召你
You. You are summoned.
这场干旱看来无止尽了
This drought seems never to end.
你怎么过活
How do you fare?
主人养活我
Domina provides for me.
很好
That's good.
Good.
你服侍主人多久了
How long have you served domina?
一辈子
All my life.
我出生于这个训练场
I was born in this ludus.
真是女大十八变
And recently come to blossom.
以前我都没留意到你
I barely noticed till I
三天前在竞技场上看到你跟着主人
I saw you at the games with Domina three moons past
当时我对战塔克尼城的阿诺克
I fought Arnoch of Tarquinii.
我的胜利给你带来愉悦了吗
Did you enjoy my victory?
结束的时候 是的
I was pleased. When it ended.
要割下一个人的头颅并非易事
It's no easy task to sever a man's head.
角度要找对
You must find the right angle.
其实我不喜欢看竞技
I do not favor the games.
这可很罕见
Well that is an odd bent
尤其对一个奴隶而言
For a slave
一个角斗士学校的奴隶
At a gladiator school.
真是朽木不可雕
One not to be straightened.
我并无意冒犯
I did not mean to insult.
主人等着呢
Domina awaits.
你走得可真慢
You walk too slowly to my chambers.
我不想让人怀疑
I do not want to arouse the suspicions
我来此的目的
Of my men as to my purpose.
你目的何在呢 卡普亚的冠军
And what might that be oh champion of Capua?
主人之所欲 即我之所求
Whatever Domina desires.
为了晚宴 我买了这条项链
I brought this necklace for the reception…
你觉得它太花哨了吗
Do you think its too much?
我血脉喷张了
My blood rises.
但并不是项链的功劳
But to give the necklace credit would be false.
那么是什么使得你心跳加速呢
And what quickens your pulse?
你的双唇
The touch of your lips.
你的酥胸
Your breasts…
以及那下体的愉悦
And all of the pleasures below…
我要你操我
I need your cock inside me.
就现在
And I need it in me now.
永远不能走神
Never lose focus!
即使是朱庇特神
Not if Jupiter himself
下凡人间
Were to rip open the heavens
他也会谨慎行事
And dangle his cock from the skies!
一招不慎 乾坤难回
A gladiator's first distraction is his last.
但并不是所有对决都以死亡告终
Not all contests end in death…
竖起二指
Two fingers.
表示投降之意
A sign of surrender.
亦是耻辱
And shame.
我立下的誓言里可不包括求饶
The oath I swore to this place did not including begging.
他是好奇…
He inquires as to the nuances of…
我不识「投降」二字
I need no lesson in submission.
想认识其他的字吗
You favor a different lesson?
教教你「服从」二字怎么写
In obedience perhaps?
下粪池去
To the hole!
两个都去
Both of you!
可能我是冒失了点
Perhaps I spoke out of turn.
可能
Perhaps?
我以为你勇敢 看来只是鲁莽
What I perceived as courage in you reveals itself foolishness.
在竞技场上求饶 我办不到
To surrender in the arena…I cannot do.
我必须赢
I must have victory.
可要是你赢不了呢
What happens when that is something you cannot provide?
学着闭嘴
Silence then.
下次你再挑衅多科特
Next time you vex doctore
我肯定不帮你说话
You'll find my tongue of a similar fashion.
我不想连累你
Your company here was not my intent.
但我还是来了 跟你在这泡粪澡
Yet here I stand beside you my cock soaking in the same shit.
抱歉
Apologies.
真没诚意
well that's all?
不说点难言之隐吗
No reason behind it
不解释下为什么脑袋发热
No glimpse in to the fevered brain
干了这样的蠢事
Of what the fuck are you doing?
我只为讨好巴蒂塔斯
I seek only to please batiatus.
胡说
Pluto's asshole.
根本说不通
The answer has no balance with your actions.
他跟我许诺过
He made a promise.
你不求名利 他能许你什么
What could he offer a man who seeks neither fame nor glory.
还我妻子
My wife.
罗马人抓我时 把她一并带走了
Taken from me when I was captured by the romans.
若我能立足竞技场 他便帮我夫妻团聚
I prevail in the arena and he will find her.
她值得吗
Is she worth it?
她值得我做任何事
She's worth everything.
我也一样
As is mine.
花两年时间
Two years here.
用我的奖金还清债务
Pay my debts with the winnings.
我就会重返她身边
Hold her in my arms again.
这身污秽到时候肯定能洗干净了吧
Perhaps the smell will have washed off by then.
她叫什么名字
What name do you call her?
奥瑞莉娅
Aurelia.
你妻子呢
Yours?
苏拉
Sura.
那么
So.
这么泡粪澡
Buried up to your balls in garbage.
是你与苏拉团聚的计划之一吗
Is part of your plan to get sura back?
就这么点供给水 都拿去洗这小布条
You'd waste your ration cleaning a bit of cloth?
这布条对我很重要
It bears meaning to me.
集合
Gather.
经过主人的慎重考虑
Your master's hand has been at work.
拟定了锻造神之节的对阵名单
The pairings of the vulcanalia have been decided.
克雷斯
Crixus!
卡普亚的不败战神
The unbeaten champion of capua.
你将代表巴蒂塔斯家族
You will honor the house of batiatus
担任骁将
By fighting in his primus!
谁与我对阵 多科特
And who will challenge me doctore?
此人技艺高超 兢兢业业
A man of skill and dedication.
他的能力 他的刻苦 及对胜利的欲望
His ability his hard work and his hunger
必须得到奖赏与满足
Shall be rewarded.
尼亚斯
Gnaeus!
英雄相见 兄弟
At last we meet brother.
撑着点 别太早翘辫子
Don't die to quickly.
我吗
Me?
我会奸了你的尸
I will fuck your corpse.
你要用啥奸
With what cock?
余下名单由阿舒尔公布
Ashur carries the remainder.
神明与你们同在
May the gods be with you!
一个一个来
One by one.
一个一个来 兔崽子们
One by one you fucking cunts!
这可是巴蒂塔斯亲手交给我的
Batiatus himself handed me this list…
贱人 拿来
Give it here shit fuck.
野蛮的家伙
Savages.
操
Fucking cock.
我看看
Let me see it.
拿过来
Give it here.
你会上场吗
Did you gain position?
跟你一样
As did you.
我们俩对阵 打头炮
We are set to fight each other at the start of the games.
第一场
The first match?!
让我们当无名小卒
The slot of the meek and insubstantial!
那就得证明我们不是
We shall prove otherwise.
为了什么
To what aim?
胜者奖金不过半文钱
The victor's purse won't be more than half a coin.
这么点
So little?
对我们俩的情况根本是于事无补
Not enough for either of our causes.
如果是作为骁将呢
And for the primus?
会多很多
Considerably more.
测试的时候 我打败过克雷斯
I already bested crixus once in the final test.
现在我得再一路杀过这些废物
Now I must fight my way up through the dregs
才能再次和他对阵
To face him again?
说我是废物吗
Dregs am I?
你知道我的意思
You know my meaning.
如果不是巴蒂塔斯阻止我
If batiatus hadn't stayed my hand
我早让他身首异处了
I would have parted his brains from his skull.
我和克雷斯没什么过结
There is no love lost between myself and crixus…
只是提醒一句 他可是危险人物
But I caution he's dangerous.
他到底哪来的名声
A reputation built on what?
对阵挥舞小渔网的尼亚斯之流吗
Facing men such as gnaeus and his little net?
克雷斯打败的可是大人物
Crixus forged his reputation against far worse.
完全是来自地狱的恶魔
Demons belched from the underworld.
加根兄弟
the gargan twins.
德修斯和提比略
Decimus and tiberius.
豺狼之子
Sons of a whore raped by a jackel.
人面兽心
More beasts than men.
一直以来是东部沿海人的心头大患
They terrorized the eastern seaboard for many years
直到他们被捕获
Until their capture.
本想让他们葬身竞技场
They were cast into the arena to die.
反倒满足了他们杀戮的欲望
But instead flourished on meals of bone and blood…
那些壮汉还没失去意识就被大卸八块
The bodies of stout men left in their wake half devoured.
没人敢自愿挑战他们
No one dared face them willingly.
唯有一人例外
Except for one…
卡普亚的冠军 克雷斯
Crixus! Champion of capua!
血流成河 吼声震天
The blood flowed. The crowd roared.
恶魔全都倒在他剑下
And the demons fell beneath his sword…
豺狼之子吗
The sons of a jackal?
传闻如此
So they say.
这故事真荒谬
The story is a jest.
就像克雷斯一样
Like Crixus himself.
你听说过吗
Did you hear this one?!
也许有一天你能证明自己
One day maybe you prove yourself.
但之前 你只配在早场跟那些废物过招
'til then you fight at dawn with the rest of the shitwhores.
我与强大的斯巴达克斯并驾齐驱
I keep pace with the mighty Spartacus.
还当我是废物吗
Still place my worth among the dregs?
我说错话了
I misspoke.
我们要打一场 对吧
A theme with you is it not?
我会称你为对手
I shall call you equal.
其它的你要自己争取
More will need to be earned.
会是场精彩的对决
It will be a good fight.
愿神明保佑我们都活下来
May the gods see us both survive.
这里很多人都会死
There are many I would see dead in this place.
你不在其中
You are not among them though.
也许你别无选择
You may not have a choice.
船到桥头自然直
There is always a choice.
你的表情让人担心
That look gives me worry.
我妻子经常这么说
Words I've heard often from my wife.
你的对手可真是个人物啊 尼亚斯
Your net's aim is remarkably true Gnaeus.
你的动作相当漂亮
You strike an impressive figure.
可惜只是对付个小木人
Battling that little wooden man.
我真想见识你场上的雄姿
I long to see you in the arena.
跟货真价实的角斗士决斗
Among the men there you are…
手里拿着一张可怕的网子
With your fearsome net!
像个骚娘们
Like a young wet girl.
兔崽子
Fucking cunt!
骄阳把尼亚斯烤疯了
The sun has made Gnaeus mad.
他像头发狂的山羊冲过来
He charged like crazed goat.
我看到他的眼睛
I saw his eyes.
燃烧着狂野与饥渴
They were wild with thirst.
巴尔卡 柯泽
Barca! Kerza!
照顾尼亚斯
Tend to Gnaeus.
继续训练
Back to work!
阿舒尔
Ashur.
我需要你帮我弄点东西
There is something I want you to get for me.
不管你要什么 阿舒尔都能搞到
Whatever your needs Ashur provides.
换地方说话 防奸细之耳
Follow me away from prying ears…
看来我必须与你划清界限
I must make a point to stop standing beside you.
尼亚斯暴躁鲁莽
Gnaeus was of an unsteady nature.
如果你想取代尼亚斯出场
If your intent was to claim Gnaeus' berth in the primus
那就太傻了
you're a fool.
他干了五年才获此殊荣
He served five years before he was afforded the privilege.
苏拉可等不起
Sura cannot afford years.
如果你在竞技场
Nor your death
对上了克雷斯
which is surely your station
你就小命不保了
if you face Crixus in the arena.
角斗士们
Gladiators!
观众已经到场
Your public has arrived.
快换衣服
Dress quickly.
晚宴开始了
The reception begins.
克雷斯
Crixus!
让亲爱的蒙卡图好好看看你的剑
Let good mercato have a closer look at your sword.
遵命主人
Dominus.
就是这把剑砍倒了德修斯和提比略
The very blade used to strike down tiberius and decimus.
如果你想为卡普亚增光添彩
If you were to bestow capua with the gift of a munus
还有什么比下注克雷斯更好的呢
what better means than securing Crixus?
如果连同我其他的角斗士一并下注
Along with a dozen or so of my other offerings
就更完美了
to round out the proceedings?
看在好友的面子上 我会好好考虑的
I have been contemplating games in honor of my good friend…
阿舒尔
Ashur!
亲爱的蒙卡图有意全程下注
Good mercato has set his mind to a day of games.
你来负责满足他的要求 好吗
Let us see his order well filled…Shall we?
啊 真是又热又燥
Ahh the dust and the heat
越来越难受
it worsens by the hour.
要不是有比赛 我这会就在罗马
I'd yet be in rome if it weren't for the games.
你一定要去罗马看我
You must promise to visit while I'm here.
我父亲的公馆太无趣了
My father's villa is beyond depressing.
你丈夫不能来真是太遗憾了
It's unfortunate your husband couldn't join you.
将军近来可好
How fares the legatus?
在闹脾气
In a mood.
自打从色雷斯回来后
Since his return from thrace
元老院就成了他的情妇
The senate has become his mistress.
还对他欲求不满
Her demands on him are boundless.
男人都有野心
Men and their ambitions.
他们该学会欣赏
You know they should learn to appreciate
更美好的事物
The finer things in life.
这条项链 我非常喜欢
That necklace. I adore it.
这个吗
Oh this?
地摊货
It's a trinket.
我也有一条类似的 从拉麦尔那里买的
It calls to mind a piece I had from Ramel one season.
那时候翡翠正流行
When emerald was still the fashion.
我听说现在又开始流行了
I hear it's coming back around.
也许我该把那条翻出来
Oh. Perhaps I'll root mine out then.
新老朋友们
Friends old and new!
由衷地感谢各位今晚光临
Gratitude for honoring the storied ludus of Batiatus
我的著名的训练场
with your presence this eve.
明天的锻造神之节竞技场上将会精彩纷呈
Tomorrow's vulcanalia promises many glories in the arena.
但是今晚
But tonight…
请允许我介绍共和国内最优秀的角斗士
May I present to you the finest gladiators in all the republic!
远观
Look!
亵玩
Touch!
感受这上好的货色
Feel the quality of the stock!
挑你们喜欢的下注
Place your orders for any of the men you covet!
来吧 别害羞 他们不咬人
Come! Don't be bashful they won't bite!
要是真咬了 就打九折
And if they do a ten percent discount!
大家都喜欢我们的色雷斯人 对吧
The crowd fancies our thracian don't they?
仅仅因为他对抗索罗尼斯的角斗士出名
A curiosity born of his fortune against solonius' men.
有人喜欢总好过无人问津
Better curiosity than indifference!
也许我们能把他们的兴趣
Perhaps we could fuel this interest
变成万贯金银
Into a conflagration of coin…
由于尼亚斯颅骨受伤无法上场
With Gnaeus of questionable skull
你觉得让斯巴达克斯代表骁将出战如何
what make you of Spartacus as replacement in our primus?
恕我直言 万众期待一场精彩绝伦的竞技
With respect dominus the public seeks an honorable fight.
斯巴达克斯还不够火候
Spartacus is yet the animal.
我会考虑的
Um well I'll think on.
距离竞技赛开赛
One day though.
还有一天时间
A contest to be promoted…
孤身一人
A moment alone.
对于一个受万众崇拜的男人 真是稀奇
A rarity for a man with such an adoring public huh?
那么进入正题
To business then.
这是临时下达的一个任务 十分艰巨
A difficult task on short notice yet…
将其完成
Carried to completion.
真操蛋
Cock fucker.
这个高卢人真是赏心悦目
Your Gaul is of a fine cut is he not?
前无古人 后无来者
None finer in all the republic.
真是雄姿英发
Such a man…
我十分期待在竞技场上一睹他的风采
I tremble to see him again at the arena…
彼此彼此
As do we all.
这个色雷斯人居然还活着
The Thracian yet lives?
暂时而已
For now.
还有什么更有趣的吗
Is there nothing more of interest to see?
不久之后我丈夫就会指名骁将了
Well my husband will shortly announce his primus
而且还有充足的美酒
and there's is ample wine…
我对这些毫无兴趣
I fear it already beckons my sleep.
或许我该离开了
Perhaps I'd best take leave.
当然
Course.
我想还有一件事会让你乐在其中
Of course there is one thing that I thought you might enjoy
关于一些男女之事
Its something of a much more physical nature.
你
You.
跟我来
Come with me.
我赌五第纳尔 他撑不过二十下
Five denarii says he doesn't last another twenty strokes.
我还从没见过角斗士做爱
I've never seen a gladiator fuck before…
看那猛烈的撞击
Look at the way he rams her!
像发怒的公牛一样
Like an enraged bull!
角斗士的过人之处
A gladiator's virtues extends well beyond
数之不尽
the sands of the arena.
作为情人 他们就是饥渴难耐的野兽
As lovers they are said to be ravenous beasts.
用手感觉一下
You can touch.
原谅我 奥瑞莉娅
Oh forgive me Aurelia.
他们会让人欲仙欲死
They provide unimaginable pleasures…
他能再做一次吗
Can he do it again?
让他再做一次
Make him do it again!
继续吧
Proceed.
那么 我们意见一致了
So we are in agreement.
毛鲁斯会迎战克雷斯
Rabanus will meet Crixus.
让汉米卡填补空缺
Move Hamilcar up to fill the void.
我听说巴蒂塔斯和多科特在开会
I overheard Batiatus and Doctore in conference.
关于骁将之名落入谁手
The primus their intent.
那个撒丁人要对战克雷斯
The Sardinian is to face Crixus.
这个消息对我的现状也于事无补
The news does not balance my cause.
不管你在想什么 死心吧
Whatever your thoughts cast them out.
敬爱的子民们
Good citizens!
各位尽享了美味佳肴
You've enjoyed my food!
醇香美酒
My wine!
还目睹了我倾国倾城的妻子的美貌
The aphrodisiac presence of my beautiful wife!
现在请屏息期待明日的骁将人选
Now marvel at the announcing of tomorrow's primus!
克雷斯 卡普亚的冠军
Crixus the champion of Capua
将在沙场上与其抗衡的是…
will stride across the sands and face…
斯巴达克斯
Spartacus!
不 让他们打
No! Let them fight!
够了
Enough!
我要将你碎尸万段
I will take your fucking heart!
放马过来 你个孬种
Come and take it coward!
仇恨使其怒火中烧 锐不可当
See their hatred burning beyond control!
今日点到为止 且等明日
This was merely a taste!Tomorrow
看其沙场之上 短兵相接
they will settle this grudge in the arena!
克雷斯 无往不胜
Crixus the undefeated!
斯巴达克斯 逆天而行
Spartacus the dog who defies death!
世纪之战
A fight for the ages!
卡普亚之荣耀
Glory to capua!
罗马之荣耀
Glory to rome!
晚宴几乎被他毁了
The reception nearly ruined
而对他的处罚是什么呢
and what is his punishment?
居然让他当骁将
The fucking primus!
你听到众人的呼声了
You heard the crowd.
我做出了最合情合理的决定
I made the best of a situation.
那个色雷斯人根本没有作为角斗士出战过
The Thracian has yet to stand a single match as gladiator.
为什么众人之中选他来迎战克雷斯
Why leap him ahead of all others to face Crixus?
因为他挑起了
Because of what he possesses.
民众的兴致
The public's interest.
他们居然对条疯狗宠爱有加
They stroke a rabid dog.
斯巴达克斯让众人为之震撼
Spartacus has struck a chord.
我打算最大限度地利用这点 从中获利
I intend to maximize its profit.
他的行为反复无常 他藐视规则
He's unpredictable he has no regard for rules
目中无人 如果克雷斯出什么意外的话
or for honor and if something happens to Crixus…
他对克雷斯构不成任何威胁
He poses no threat to Crixus.
大家对他只是一时兴起
He is but a novelty.
热度过后 自然将他抛之脑后
To be used and discarded after a purpose.
他妈的 没有酒了吗
Fucking god's cock is there no wine left!
你还愣在那干什么
Well what are you standing there for
去拿酒啊
go and get some fucking wine.
抱歉
Apologies.
我没想吓你
I did not mean to startle.
我们上一次谈话 我并无冒犯之意
When we spoke last I meant no offense.
我擅长舞刀弄枪 不会舞文弄墨
I am practiced with sword not words.
如果主人发现我打破了最后一壶酒
If domina discovers I dropped the last jug…
把碎片给我
Hand me the pieces.
我会把它们处理掉
I'll see them over the cliff.
等等
Wait.
借此物以表达我难以言喻之情
Perhaps this gift will explain where words fail.
请收下
Please.
我在试着作出决定
I'm trying to decide.
决定什么
Upon what?
祝贺你还是悼念你
Congratulations or condolences.
你痛打了克雷斯 是因为
You may have bested Crixus once by tripping him
他毫无防备
with that bit of cloth
可在竞技场上与其对战
But to face him in the arena…
我坚信他徒有虚名
I believe his reputation inflated.
明天我会证明这点
Tomorrow I shall prove it so.
接下来你会吹牛说 瑟奥科斯也是手下败将
Next he'll boast he can defeat Theokoles himself.
或许吧
Perhaps.
前提是我得认识他
If I knew the man.
瑟奥科斯
Theokoles.
死亡之影
The shadow of death.
他对竞技场不屑一顾
He speaks so brazenly of the arena
他对其历史一无所知
He knows nothing of its history.
瑟奥科斯并非凡人 色雷斯人
Theokoles is no man Thracian.
他完全是…
He is something else entirely…
传说他有十英尺高
They say he stand over ten feet tall.
所到之处 地动山摇
The very ground trembles at his feet.
月残日殇
His shadow eclipsing the sun.
许多人光是见他一面就已被吓死
Most men fall dead at the sight of the giant.
他们算是幸运的
They are the fortunate ones.
我父亲说与「死亡之影」
My father tells of a munus
交过手的角斗士超过百人
in which the shadow fought over a hundred men.
可他们无一生还
Not one survived.
那只是一个传说 吓唬小孩子的
A tale to frighten children.
瑟奥科斯不是传说
Theokoles is no legend.
他还活跃在竞技场上的时候
Before he retired from the arena
与他交手过的只有一人生还
only one man ever faced him and lived.
这个人就在我们中间
And he breathes among us
他就是鞭打我们的多科特
his whip ever at our backs.
现在可不是闲话家常的时候
Now is not the hour for idle talk.
明天你们将奔赴竞技场
Tomorrow you step into the arena.
你们中的许多人是首次登台
Many for the first time.
对于有些人 可能也是最后一次
For some perhaps the last.
他们为鲜血欢呼
They cheer for blood.
我会让他们得偿所愿的
And they shall have it.
愿神明保佑你 正如今早我被他们护佑一般
May the gods bring you fortune as they did me this morning.
苏拉信仰神明
Sura believed in the gods.
可当罗马人要带走她的时候
And when the Romans took her
可没有哪位神明出面加以阻挠
not one descended from the heavens to intervene.
不久我将会纠正他们所犯下的错
I shall correct their mistake presently.
我相信你做的到
I believe you will.
人们喜欢你安排的这些比赛
The crowd favors your offerings.
是的 这是一场精彩的演出
Yes a fine showing all around.
巴蒂塔斯 卡普亚以你为豪
You honor our fair city Batiatus.
我很荣幸 行政官
The honor is mine magistrate.
恕我直言 我本以为这场比赛
Truth told I feared the event would
将乏善可陈
pass without anything of note this year.
要想诱使重量级的选手来此参加
Its very difficult to procure men of worth
这些小比赛并非易事
for these minor games.
索罗尼斯的缺席使得这场比赛逊色不少
Good Solonius was already taken with loftier engagements.
索罗尼斯明年或许能来
Perhaps Solonius will be available next year.
我们唯有向上天祷告
One can but pray.
早知道如此干旱 我就不回来了
Perhaps I was wrong to return absent the rain.
喝点水吗
Some water perhaps.
还是喝点酒
Or maybe some wine.
一想到酒 我的胃里就翻江倒海
Uhh the thought churns the stomach.
不过昨晚你的招待真是让我欢悦有加
Your company last night yet astounds the senses.
过头了吗
Too much?
如果说酒的话 是的
Of wine definitely.
至于其他的…
Of other interests…
只是隔靴搔痒
I think the surface barely scratched.
那就喝点水吧 以缓解你目前的饥渴
Some water then to slake your current thirst.
我们开始吧
Here we go then.
卡普亚的子民们
Good citizens of Capua!
我很荣幸的向你们引荐
It is my great honor to introduce to you the primus
巴蒂塔斯的骁将
of Quintus Lentulus Batiatus!
色雷斯人进场
Enter Thraex!
有请 斯巴达克斯
Behold Spartacus!
斯巴达克斯 斯巴达克斯
Spartacus! Spartacus!
他以在阿比努斯元老的赛场上
Renowned for his magnificent victory
取得的斐然成绩而闻名于世
at the games of Senator Albinius!
他单枪匹马
Where he single handedly
战胜了四名索罗尼斯的角斗士
slaughtered four of Solonius' gladiators!
四名啊
Four!
姆尔米洛进场
Enter Murmillo!
他的战绩世人有目共睹
The marvel before you needs no introduction!
他以剑术精进
He's known by his sword!
擅于用盾以及辉煌的战绩闻名于世
By his shield! By his glory!
克雷斯
Crixus!
卡普亚的冠军
The champion of Capua!
我终于见到克雷斯了
Finally Crixus!
瞧他在骄阳下的矫健身姿
Look how his form catches the sun!
卡普亚
Capua!
以巴蒂塔斯和神圣的锻造神之节之名…
In honor of the name Batiatus and the sacred Vulcanalia…
你的致辞尚未结束
You had not yet finished the oration
那个色雷斯人竟然开战了
and yet the Thracian attacks!?!
难道不该这样的吗
Was that not supposed to happen?
不 当然不是
No it was not.
真刺激
How exciting…
色雷斯人就这么点能耐吗
Is that all the Thracian is capable of?
看过他和索罗尼斯的手下决斗过以后
After what he did against Solonius' men
我对他可是寄予厚望啊
I had hoped for more.
卡普亚
Capua!
我该继续吗
Shall I begin!?!
你的死期到了 色雷斯人
Now you die Thracian.
杀了他 杀了他
Kill. Kill.
Kill kill.
杀了他 杀了他
Kill kill!
斯巴达克斯的表现很精彩
Spartacus fought well!
让他活命 日后再战吧
Let him live to fight another day!
如此结局 真是扫兴
A sour bite to end the meal.
抱歉
Apologies.
我在斯巴达克斯身上花了大价钱
Yet Spartacus was of some cost to me…
你已失去民心
You've already lost the crowd.
竟然让他活下来了
He lives?
真没劲
How disappointing.
他真是实至名归
His reputation is well earned.
他的战术无懈可击
My blade could find no weakness.
可他还是有漏洞的
And yet… it was there.
他有至少十处破绽 你本可以操胜券的
At least ten points where you could have seized advantage.
你的战技还需淬炼
You needed more training.
我会加倍努力训练的
I shall train harder then.
不必了
No.
为时已晚
It is too late for such things.